chapter six
Oh, little prince!
Bit by bit I came to understand the
secrets of your sad little life...
For a long time you had found your only
entertainment in the quiet pleasure of
looking at the sunset.
I learned that new detail on the morning
of the fourth day, when you said to me:
"I am very fond of sunsets.
Come, let us go and look at the sunset
now."
"But we must wait," I said.
"Wait?
For what
wait For the sun to set We must wait
until it is time."
At first you seem to be very much
surprised.
And then you left yourself and said to
me
I'm always thinking that I'm at home!"
Just so
everyone knows that when it is noon in
the United States the sun is setting
over France.
If you could just fly in one minute to
France you could go straight into the
sunset,
right from noon.
Unfortunately, France is too far away for
that.
But on your tiny little planet
all you need to do is to move your chair
a few steps
and You could see the day end
and the twilight falling whenever you
like...
"One day,"
you said to me,
"I watched the sunset 44 times!"
And a little later you added:
"You know--
one loves the sunset,
when one is so sad..."
"Were you so sad, then?" I asked,
"on the day you watched those 44 sunsets?"
But the little prince
made no reply
foreign